Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [INFORMATION

Notice Period: 3 Months

SCIENCE]





Senior Associate seeking roles in IT Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Development, Software Development, SDLC, Release Management, Software Design, PHP, jQuery, Angularjs, Apache Tomcat, Mysql



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: GyanMatrix Technologies

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Canada

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Associate. Software Developer, IT Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Development, Software Development, SDLC, Release Management, Software Design, PHP, iQuery, Angularis

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Achievement-driven professional with an experience of nearly 8 years

Comprehensive experience in designing systems/ procedures for change in project operations to design technical solutions, ensuring business functionality adherence and enhancing competitive advantage

Insightful knowledge of business process analysis and design, application based process optimization, and cost control and revenue maximization from various solutions

Experience in analysis practice with proven capabilities in capturing as-is process, preparing functional specifications, & business blueprint document, analysing the gaps

Developed real-time web applications, complex back-end management systems including content management and ecommerce

Developed software solutions by studying needs, conferring with users, studying systems flow, data usage and work processes

# Work Experience

GyanMatrix Technologies as Senior Software Engineer Aug 2020 to Aug 2020

Creating web-based applications for Education platform and contributing in many aspects of Learnship team such as: developing REST API using Symfony, developing front end application using ReactJS, and built corn job (queuing) system using NodeJS and python (Airflow)

GyanMatrix Technologies as Senior Software Engineer Aug 2020 to Till Date

Symphony Talent as Senior Associate-IT Application Jul 2018 to Aug 2020

Key Result Areas:

Creating back-end applications for dynamic websites and contributing in many aspects of ST team such as: developing

API using Java, Custom WordPress plugins, PHP websites using PHP based frameworks like WordPress Performing as a Full Stack Developer, steering team management, developing high level design and story estimation

#### Harman Connected Service as Senior Software Developer

Feb 2016 to Jun 2018

Key Result Areas:

Creating back-end applications for dynamic websites and contributing in many aspects of ST team such as: developing

API using Java, Custom WordPress plugins, PHP websites using PHP based frameworks like WordPress Performing as a Full Stack Developer, steering team management, developing high level design and story estimation

### Inkoniq, Bangalore as PHP Developer

Jun 2015 to Feb 2016

Mainly responsible for developing backend applications for dynamic websites. I play a hands-on roll in many aspects of Inkoniq team such as:

- + Building PHP websites using PHP based frameworks like Drupal, WordPress.
- + Worked in Manipal Global Education Service as consultant and responsibilities are -
- o Provide support to Online learning system known as smude.
- o Developed custom modules for Drupal platform in which smude was built

### Blukraft as PHP Developer

May 2014 to Jun 2015

Mainly responsible for developing backend applications for dynamic websites. I play a hands-on roll in many aspects of Blukraft team such as:

- + Building PHP websites using PHP based frameworks.
- + Planning and conducting cross-browser usability testing against W3C.
- + Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- + Developing advanced database driven websites & Developing advanced database driven database database driven database driven
- + Back end development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- + Developing compatible User Interface functionality using jQuery& other libraries.
- + Developing web sites using MySQL, PHP & Deve
- + Documenting features, technical specifications & Documenting features, technical spe
- + Working with a multidisciplinary team to convert business needs into technical specifications.

#### ISRO-Indian Space Research Organization-Telemetry Tracking and Command Network (ISTRAC)

as Graduate Apprentice Trainee

Oct 2013 to May 2014

Responsible for Establishing and Improving the Reliability and Quality Standards of ISTRAC. I play a hands-on roll in many aspects of Reliability and Quality Assurance (REQA) team whose focus areas include the following:

- + Provide IT(Software) solution for REQA using PHP and MySQL technology
- + Main responsible in Automating Test Instrument Facility (TIF)
- + Carrying out Test & Dry; Evaluation of the Ground Elements as per the requirement ( T & Dry; E)
- + Configuration control of the launch supporting Ground Elements as per the requirement (CCB)
- + Support calibration of Electronic Instruments used during launch and tracking of satellite

### Menestys Solutions as Software Developer

Jun 2012 to Jun 2013

Job role played are -

+ Business Analyst, Database Design, Web development, testing.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (INFORMATION SCIENCE) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2012

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

**API Platform** 

API Platform Part2: Security

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last	t Used	Experience
PHP, Java, NodeJS			
HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Jquery,			
Ajax, AngularJS, Backbone JS			
Opencart, CMS, MVC, CS Cart, PHP			
Apache Tomcat 2.4.4			
WINDOWS			
MySQL 5.6, Oracle			

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
tamil	Expert			
kannada	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
Telugu	Beginner			

## **Affirmative Action**

Category: OBC - Creamy

Physically Challenged: No

### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time